

# Adel Ferdjoukh

#### Software Architect



29 years



Toulouse, France +33 695 55 89 13



www.adel-ferdjoukh.ovh



ferdjoukh@gmail.com

## About me ——

I obtained a PhD. in computer science (software engineering). I worked as a researcher and university teacher in several labs in France and Austria. Currently, I am a technical leader at Altran in Toulouse. I am responsible of an R&D project and I supervise developers for client projects on Model Based Software Engineering and Agile Frameworks.

# Skills -

Model Based Software Engineering

Java

Eclipse EMF, RCP

Shell

Agile frameworks

Project Management

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

### Experience

since 2019 Software Technical Leader

Altran Technologies

I joined Altran as a software developer in Model Based Software and Java. I became the leader of an R&D project. Currently, I am the technical leader for *Model Based Software Engineering* offers and I

supervise developers on client projects (eg. Airbus)

2018 Researcher & Teacher Technische Universitat Wien

I was conducting research on Model Driven Engineering and I gave

courses on Graphical Modelling in English

2016-2018 Researcher & Teacher Universite de Nantes

I was responsible of students groups for many computer science courses: programming, databases, web programming and I con-

ducted researches on Model Driven Engineering

2013-2016 Young Researcher Universite de Montpellier

I was preparing my PhD in computer science in *Lirmm* research lab and teaching computer science courses in the *Faculty of Sciences* 

## **Education**

2013-2016 Ph.D. candidate in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

A Declarative Approach for Model Generation

2012-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Montpellier

Specializing in Software Engineering

2011-2013 Master in Computer Science Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in Networks and Distributed Systems

2008-2011 Bachelor Universite de Bejaia

Specializing in mathematics and informatics.

#### Notable Facts

Publications 10 papers in journal, international conferences or workshops

Best Paper ICSEA 2017, Athens, Greece

Talks Montpellier, Nantes, Lille, Angers, Paris, Bordeaux, Washington DC,

San Francisco, Oslo, Copenhagen, Athens & Vienna.

Teaching +700 hours teaching in 3 universities and +10 different topics.

Industrials Airbus, Dassault, Safran
Certification Professional Scrum Master I

# Projects

HQ Workbe. Architect & Scrum Master Airbus

Digital Transformation of HQ Data and Tools

IPad Technical Leader Airbus

A workbench for aerodynamics studies

Icing Technical Leader & Developer Airbus

A Workbench for Icing Tools & Data

Optimind R&D Project Leader Altran Research

A Model-Driven toolbox for engineers

Rumor Developer Airbus

Automate and migrate simulation tools

Grimm Architect & Developer Lirmm

**Automatic Model Generator** 

# [Languages]

French, English, Arabic, Kabyle, German (beginner)

# Interests

Travel, History, Geography and Sport.